Teaching Support Staff Union fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Stewards' reports, 1976 - 1983; F-38-6; 5 cm of textual records
  - Chief Stewards' reports, 1980 - 1981; F-38-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Stewards' notices and lists, 1980 - 1981; F-38-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Stewards' seminars, 1976 - 1977; F-38-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Capilano College arbitration and grievance seminar, 1981; F-38-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
- Finance, 1980 - 1987; F-38-7; 1 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to TSSU's financial accounting and audit. It comprises an incomplete sequence of financial statements and audit reports.
  - Financial statements, 1980 - 1987; F-38-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
- Communications, 1977 - 1982; F-38-8; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to TSSU publicity and the provision of information to members and potential members, together with some anti-TSSU material. TSSU activities documented include appealing to and educating potential bargaining unit members, publicizing established rights, gathering information, and the maintenance of existing members' awareness of current union activities. Records include notices and letters for and against the union, runs of La Chispa, La Chispa Bulletin, Bulletin, and TSSU/AUCE 6 Bulletin, a questionnaire, correspondence, press releases and clippings.
  - La Chispa, 1977 - 1979; F-38-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - TSSU Bulletin, 1980 - 1982; F-38-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Membership bulletins, information, 1977 - 1980; F-38-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Membership bulletins, questionnaire, 1978 - 1979; F-38-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Press releases, clippings, 1979 - 1980; F-38-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Publicity and correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-38-8-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
  - Anti-TSSU notices, press items, 1979 - 1980; F-38-8-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 38-11)
- Liaison, 1971 - 1988; F-38-9; 71 cm of textual records
  Series consists of three sub-series of records relating to TSSU's involvement with AUCE Provincial, its sister locals, and other unions and union organizations. Activities documented include participation in provincial conventions and committees, liaison with AUCE locals, and the exchange of information with other unions and provincial and national labour organizations. Provincial records include the AUCE Provincial constitution, policies and procedures; convention agendas, reports, minutes, proposals, resolutions, and press releases; Affiliation Committee agendas, minutes, transcripts, reports and bulletins; Executive Committee agendas, local reports, financial statements, minutes and correspondence; and provincial bulletins and resource lists. Local records include by-laws; committee reports and minutes; correspondence; bulletins, press releases and press clippings; cross-local packages; and Labour Relations Board appeals. Other union records include, variously, constitutions and collective agreements; bargaining unit profiles, handbooks and information sheets; reports and newsletters; and resolutions and correspondence with such organizations as the Service, Office and Retail Workers' Union of Canada (SORWUC); the B.C. Federation of Labour; and the Confederation of Canadian Unions.
  Association of University and College Employees, Local 2; Service, Office, and Retail Workers Union of Canada
  - AUCE Provincial, F-38-9-1
    - Provincial constitution, 1982; F-38-9-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - Provincial policies and procedures, 1976; F-38-9-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - Provincial Council agenda, minutes, 1987 - 1988; F-38-9-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 1st and 2nd AUCE conventions and 1975 special convention, 1974 - 1975; F-38-9-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 3rd AUCE convention, 1976; F-38-9-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 4th AUCE convention, 1977; F-38-9-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 5th AUCE convention (resolutions), 1978; F-38-9-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 5th AUCE convention (minutes), 1978; F-38-9-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 6th AUCE convention, 1979; F-38-9-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 6th AUCE convention (docket), 1979; F-38-9-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 6th AUCE convention: photos 1, 1979; F-38-9-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - 6th AUCE convention: photos 2, 1979; F-38-9-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 38-12)
    - Convention minutes 1974-1979, F-38-9-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - 7th AUCE convention, 1980; F-38-9-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - 7th AUCE convention (docket), 1980; F-38-9-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - Local reports to 7th annual convention, 1980; F-38-9-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - AUCE Provincial Affiliation Committee, 1979 - 1980; F-38-9-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - Affiliation Committee reports and minutes, 1980; F-38-9-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - Affiliation correspondence, bulletins, 1980 - 1981; F-38-9-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - Special convention on affiliation, 1980; F-38-9-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - 1980 special convention, F-38-9-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - 8th AUCE convention, 1981; F-38-9-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - Provincial conventions 1977-1981, F-38-9-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 38-13)
    - 9th AUCE convention, 1982; F-38-9-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - 10th AUCE convention, 1983; F-38-9-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - 11th AUCE convention, 1984; F-38-9-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - Provincial committee nomination notice, 1980; F-38-9-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial election results, 1981; F-38-9-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly minutes 1/3, 1976; F-38-9-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly minutes 2/3, 1976 - 1977; F-38-9-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly minutes 3/3, 1977 - 1978; F-38-9-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive minutes, 1976 - 1979; F-38-9-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly minutes, 1978 - 1979; F-38-9-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly agenda, minutes, 1977 - 1981; F-38-9-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 38-14)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly agenda, minutes 1/2, 1979 - 1980; F-38-9-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - AUCE Provincial executive monthly agenda, minutes 2/2, 1979 - 1980; F-38-9-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - AUCE Provincial executive minutes, 1981; F-38-9-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - AUCE Provincial executive minutes, 1982; F-38-9-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - AUCE provincial representatives reports, 1979 - 1980; F-38-9-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Provincial executive correspondence, 1971 - 1981; F-38-9-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Provincial correspondence, 1979 - 1981; F-38-9-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Correspondence received, 1981; F-38-9-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Provincial/Local 6 correspondence, 1976 - 1977; F-38-9-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Publications, 1976 - 1981; F-38-9-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
    - Publications, [ca 1977] - [ca 1981]; F-38-9-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 38-15)
  - AUCE locals, F-38-9-2
    - Local 2 (SFU), 1976 - 1980; F-38-9-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 2 (SFU), 1977 - 1980; F-38-9-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 2 (SFU): Industrial Inquiry Commission brief 1/2, 1979; F-38-9-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 2 (SFU): Industrial Inquiry Commission brief 2/2, 1979; F-38-9-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 2 (SFU): collective agreements, 1985 - 1988; F-38-9-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 3 (Nelson, B.C.), 1976 - 1977; F-38-9-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 4 (Capilano College), 1976 - 1981; F-38-9-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 4 (Capilano College), 1978 - 1980; F-38-9-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 5 (College of New Caledonia, Prince George), 1976 - 1981; F-38-9-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
    - Local 7 (University of Victoria), 1984; F-38-9-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 38-16)
  - Other unions, F-38-9-3
    - SFU student unions, 1978 - 1979; F-38-9-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - Association of Teaching Assistants (UBC), 1977 - 1979; F-38-9-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - Graduate Assistants Association (University of Toronto), 1973 - 1980; F-38-9-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - SORWUC (SFU), 1976 - 1980; F-38-9-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - SORWUC (national), 1976 - 1981; F-38-9-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - SORWUC-United Bank Workers section 1/2, 1977 - 1980; F-38-9-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
    - SORWUC-United Bank Workers section 2/2, 1977 - 1980; F-38-9-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
- AUCE 2 Strike, 1975 - 1980; F-38-10; 11 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records arising from TSSU's involvement in the 1979 AUCE 2 strike over wages and temporary employee rights. Activities documented include the discussions and decisions of the TSSU Steering Committee and TSSU emergency meetings, TSSU participation in the joint Academic Penalties Committee and the Job Action Committee, members' strike action, and the actions of the SFU 18 Defense Committee. Records include agendas, minutes, motions and reports; correspondence and memoranda to union members, the university community, and administration; publicity materials for and against the strike, including a petition; administration, departmental and student notices and statements; bulletins, news releases and press clippings. Details of strike action are included in lists of members respecting picket lines, the picket captain's register and sign-up sheets, individual job action reports, and letters of resignation from the TSSU.
  - AUCE 2 Strike: notices, bulletins, press coverage 1/3, 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: notices, bulletins, press coverage 2/3, 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-17)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: notices, bulletins, press coverage 3/3 (incl.1975 action), 1975 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: support materials (S. Marria file), 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: "SFU 18" campaign, 1979; F-38-10-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: academic penalties, 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: TSSU correspondence, 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: Steering Committee notes (S. Marria file), 1978 - 1979; F-38-10-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: propaganda, 1979; F-38-10-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: membership register, job action reports, 1979; F-38-10-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: picketing (S. Marria file), 1979; F-38-10-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - AUCE 2 Strike: TSSU resignations, 1978 - 1980; F-38-10-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
- Operation Solidarity, 1983 - 1984; F-38-11; 5 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to TSSU's participation as an affiliate of Operation Solidarity and the Solidarity Coalition in the province-wide opposition to the 1983 Social Credit government budget and its proposed legislation. Activities documented include TSSU membership meetings and resolutions in support of the B. C. Government Employees Union and Operation Solidarity; the formation and operation of a Strike Coordination Committee; involvement in the SFU Budget Coalition; picketing and labour withdrawal; liaison with other labour organizations; and communication with SFU administration and TSSU members. Records include TSSU resolutions and strike vote sheets; SFU's affidavit and Labour Relations Board complaint against TSSU and other unions for illegal labour withdrawal and picketing; TSSU Strike Coordination Committee meeting notes; SFU Budget Coalition minutes and press releases; picket schedules, lists of participants and of those observing picket lines; motions, minutes and notices from the steering committees of Operation Solidarity and the Solidarity Coalition; bulletins and press releases from the Solidarity groups and the B.C. Federation of Labour; correspondence with SFU administration and TSSU members; and various strike and meeting notices, and press reports.
  Solidarity Coalition
  - Operation Solidarity: affidavit, complaint, picketing schedules, 1983; F-38-11-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - Operation Solidarity: TSSU strike vote, 1983; F-38-11-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - Operation Solidarity: SFU Budget Coalition 1/2, 1983; F-38-11-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - Operation Solidarity: SFU Budget Coalition 2/2, 1983; F-38-11-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - Operation Solidarity: political protest decision, 1983; F-38-11-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 38-18)
  - Operation Solidarity: bulletins and notices, 1983 - 1984; F-38-11-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 38-18)